Contact

5541457976 (Mobile) cerobles@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/cmaroblesg (LinkedIn)

cmaroblesg.github.io/ (Personal)

Top Skills

Big Data
Agile Methodologies
Python

Languages

Inglés (Full Professional)

Deutsch (Professional Working)

Español (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

Qlik Sense Business Analyst Qualification - February 2019 Release

Applied AI with DeepLearning Databases and SQL for Data Science

Python

Publications

New Characterization of an Improved Numerical Method for Solving the Electrical Impedance Equation in the Plane: An Approach from the Modern Pseudoanalytic Function Theory

Numerical algorithm for electrical impedance tomography problem using Pseudoanalytic approach

A Simplified Method for Numerically Solving the Impedance Equation in the Plane

A Simplified Method for Numerically Solving the Impedance Equation in the Plane

Sobre los Métodos Numéricos Empleados en la Ecuación de Conductividad Eléctrica

César Marco Antonio Robles González

Global WPB Financial Manager at HSBC Mexico City

Summary

Being a Financial Manager is exactly what you would think it is like. I used to check financial numbers to find errors, tendencies, patterns and even more. As a part of my current functions, I create dashboards to help the stakeholders to make decisions. The financial industry, nowadays, is under many changes due to the COVID-19 outbreak, and this will impact in the near future.

The biggest problem at this moment is to integrate the new normal with the technology. In other words, how to go to the digital transformation and not suffering in the way. Developing chat bots and doing automations using Python and R programming language could be the beginning, but also taking into considerations the artificial intelligence.

Learning is my passion and for that reason I am constantly improving and reinventing myself. Also, I love to play chess because it maintains my mind alert and thinking in the next move and respecting my adversary. But, not everything is about war and destruction, I like to play collaborative online multiplayer video games with people a long the world.

I am very organize because it makes the life easier. So, I integrate this part of my life to projects by integrating Agile Frameworks such as SCRUM. When I am not at work, I am reading and analyzing sport data, because it is easy to implement data science analysis and get some fun predicting the scores based on the last games.

At the core I am a researcher and a family man who love to have great moments with my family and my pets. Walking the dog and see how it interacts with other people and animals make me have fun most of the time. Having some time looking my cats play around the house and watching funny cat's video to try to imitate those. My wife

Bidimensional: Aproximación Pseudoanalítica

is my rock and she helps me to find my way and she makes me do my best all the time.

Feel free to reach out to have a funny talk about the new normal, chatbots, machine learning, cloud computing or anything else; don't forget that we can get it together and thrive.

Specialties: Python, Data Science, Deep Learning, Machine Learning, Cloud Computing and Automation.

Experience

HSBC

4 years 4 months

Global WPB Financial Manager April 2020 - Present (1 year 2 months) Mexico City and United Kingdom

- * Innovation Champion: Designing and coordinating new innovation projects in the America region.
- * Data Scientist: leading and designing process to extract and cleaning data, developing machine and deep learning models, constructing dashboards in Qlik Sense and Tableau, defining new data quality rules and setting-up ETL processes to data consumption.
- * Business Transformation: leading the adoption of the GCP Cloud and big data models.
- + AMG Automation: designing and leading automate processes to eliminate manual tasks.
- + Spreads Project: coordinating a local team under Scrum Framework to achieve the tasks and support the stakeholders decision making.

Global RBWM Financial Manager February 2019 - April 2020 (1 year 3 months) Mexico City and United Kingdom

- * SCRUM Master: coordinating, supporting and implementing the SCRUM Framework to work within Financial projects.
- * Data Science: Implementing and analyzing the data sources to correct issues.

- * Business Transformation Projects: Leading and coordinating projects to save time in the area.
- + Spreads project: project coordinated under SCRUM Framework. Designing a Qlik Sense Dashboard to display HSBC product information that supports the stakeholders decision making.
- + HSBC Investor Bot: leading a global project to create a Chatbot using the HSBC public information to support the Investors decision making.
- + CardBrand Bot: Coordinating and designing an automation tool to collect information from VISA, MasterCard and PROSA brands and help the stakeholders decision making.
- * Data Science Projects:
- + 24 Months Forecast Data Quality Project: Leading a global team to apply data quality rules and supporting the global teams to correct issues in the data bases. Designing a Qlik Sense Dashboard to displays the issues.
- * Mashup Projects (Web Developments): Supporting the global team and coordinating web phases to publish mashup that supports the global teams.

Specialist Consultant February 2017 - February 2019 (2 years 1 month) Mexico City

- * Data Science: leading projects and applying methodologies for the Data Quality, ETL processes, Machine Learning and Deep Learning Projects.
- * Leading Business Transformation projects:
- + Branch time motion study: Leading a team and designing a new methodology applied to the bank-branches.
- + Sherwood project: Analyzing, designing and implementing the HSBC-Group methodology to estimate the product prices.
- + Cost Management Unit project (CMU): Coordinating a visualization and Data Analytics team to implement the new methodology applied to the cost classification accounts.
- + Data Quality Analysis: implementing methodologies to analyse huge volume data and solve issues in the data.
- + Data Visualization projects: Leading visualization teams to create dynamic dashboards on Qlik Sense.

Instituto Politécnico Nacional

6 years 1 month

Phd Researcher Assistant

January 2016 - January 2017 (1 year 1 month)

Esime Culhuacan

- * Lead the Electrical Impedance Tomography project,
- * Supporting and assisting a Senior Researcher to review, wrote and graded journals.
- * Research about Data Science applied to Finance and forecasting the data.
- * Leading and coordinating Data Science Projects related to different projects on Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning.

PHD Researcher

January 2012 - January 2016 (4 years 1 month)

ESIME Culhuacan

- * Data Science: Leading, applying and coordinating teams to develop projects in Mathematics, Physics, Statistics, Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning.
- * Leading the Electrical Impedance Tomography project that implements different solutions to the direct and inverse problems. Many of the proposed solution includes the analysis of current trajectories using Artificial Intelligence, applied data analysis to the formal powers to approximate the solutions.
- * Wrote and participated in many different papers, journals and book chapters. International expositor with experienced in more than 15 congresses.

Researcher

January 2011 - December 2012 (2 years)

ESIME-Culhuacán y Universidad La Salle

- * Seismic Alert System Project (SAS): leading, coordinating and designing an Artificial Neural Network SAS to detect earthquakes that affect the Mexico-City. (IPN-CONAPRED-CIRES project)
- * Electrical Impedance Tomography project (EIT): leading and designing a new calculations forward problem using formal powers in unitary disk and complex domains.

Universidad La Salle, A.C.

2 years 8 months

Researcher

October 2009 - January 2012 (2 years 4 months)

Page 4 of 6

Mexico City, Mexico

Masters in Science Student, Cybernetics Area.

- * Leading the Electrical Impedance Tomography project (EIT): Designing and creating new hybrid algorithms based on artificial neural networks and genetic algorithms.
- * Researcher: Proposing a novelty mathematics method to solve inverse problems in the science related to the EIT.

Servers

June 2009 - October 2009 (5 months)

Mexico City, Mexico

Security practices, Servers, Tandem central.

Asterisk, Linux/Unix

School practices and internship to learn and develop special projects for the Engineering faculty at Universidad La Salle

Accival

Junior Developer

October 2006 - March 2007 (6 months)

Mexico City Metropolitan Area

Java Junior Developer: Working in the Acci-trade project developing a tool for the investors to trade and check their investments.

Laboratorio de Computo de Ingenieria de la Universidad La Salle Junior Developer

August 2005 - October 2006 (1 year 3 months)

Universidad La Salle

Visual Studio and Java Developer intern: Developing and working in several projects for La Salle University.

Education

I.P.N ESIME

Doctor of Philosophy - PhD, Communications and Electronics (2012 - 2016)

Universidad La Salle México

Masters in Science, Cybernetics Area, Cibérnetica · (2009 - 2011)

Universidad La Salle México

Bachelor's degree on Engineering, Bachelors degree in Cybernetics Engineering and Computing Systems · (2004 - 2008)